Let me first honour the great men of God and servants of God here today.
I thank God for their lives and for giving their lives to be used.
I also want to honour all the professionals.
We know that everything big starts little.
Hallelujah.
Thank you.
South Korea Crusade
I want you to pray for me; just stretch your hand and pray for me.
I need your prayer.
South Korea Crusade
Thank you.
Amen.
South Korea Crusade
Thank you.
Hallelujah.
In Jesus' name.
Yes, I'm strong!
Thank you.
Whatever situations you are going through..they are the soil on which faith grows.
I don’t know what you are going through.
Has your faith been tested now
or have you been tested in the past?
Cool down and relax.
South Korea Crusade
The answer to your test is in the Word of God.
Here is the Word of God – the Bible.
The Bible is the food for your soul – your spiritual weapon.
It has healing power.
South Korea Crusade
It has a purifying power.
It is enduring.
It rejoices the heart.
It keeps us from error and sin.
It is profitable.
This is the Bible.
This will lead us to our title today
"Situation strengthen one's faith".
The situation I went through today -
we missed our way when we were coming.
We were looking for the road.
That strengthened my faith the more.
South Korea Crusade
Situations strengthen one's faith.
Whatever you do now that is not in line with God's agenda,
that seems to prosper,
will probably disappoint you in your greatest time of need.
What I am doing is God's agenda for me;
that is why we could reach here and at the same time, my faith strengthened.
Because what you are doing is God's agenda for you,
that is why your situation has not destroyed you before coming here.
The ups and downs we see in the world today
are practical examples of not following up on God's agenda.
You are worried and upset about many things.
Your business is not doing well, your family is not doing well; in your health, there are challenges.
Let me take you to the book of John, chapter 16.
Let me just read the last verse there.
"I have told you these things, so that in me you may have peace.
In this world you will have tribulation. But take heart! I have overcome the world."
South Korea Crusade
That you are on God's agenda, you depend on God – total dependence upon God,
does not mean you will not be touched.
South Korea Crusade
Sickness will test you, hardship will test you, tribulation will test you but they cannot destroy you.
They cannot destroy you.
According to John 16:33, 'In this world, there will be tribulation. Cheer up'.
'Cheer up' means to have confidence, hope.
'Cheer up, I have overcome the world.'
This means tribulation, sickness, disease, whatever you call it, will test you
but cannot destroy you.
Whatever brought you here today...
I'm right by saying "whatever brought you here", whatever brought us here, including me...
Because everyone has limitation.
You are because I am; I am because you are.
That is, there is something I cannot do that you do for me – you translate for me.
I cannot stand here, talking and translating for myself.
That is my weakness.
You are sitting down, listening to me.
As I am talking to you, I cannot sit down at the same time.
You too cannot stand here, talking.
My weakness is – I cannot stand here and at the same time sit down. That is my weakness.
Everyone has limitation.
This is why I say, "Whatever brought you here today".
Whatever brought us here today.
I came here because I want to talk to someone.
I want to talk to someone in Korea.
Yes – that is what brought me here.
Whatever brought you here is only a weapon God uses to preserve you.
If I was not here today, who knows what would have happened to me in Nigeria?
So, I am here to be preserved.
Your sickness is meant to preserve you, to reform you.
It may equally be to keep you for a new level in life.
As a Christian, whatever level we find ourselves, we always believe the best is yet to come.
Situations strengthen our faith.
As a Christian, don’t despair at all.
Unfavourable circumstances,
I mean, unfavourable situations are the arguments satan uses
to make people of God question their sonship.
Thank you, I'm happy. I discover you.
I want to join you now.
Unfavourable circumstances are the arguments satan uses
to make people of God question their sonship.
The devil wants us to curse God while under pain, trouble, temptation,
to look at God in a bad light.
Those who bless God in trouble, tribulation, prove their sonship.
South Korea Crusade
Oh my God, I need to take my water too.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Those who bless God in trouble, tribulation, prove their sonship.
Prove their sonship.
Don’t allow your situation to rule you.
The rich must not concentrate on their wealth
because a man can be poor and yet be a friend of God, a candidate of Heaven.
Stop thinking about your situation; don’t allow your situation to rule you
because a man can be sick in body and yet, be a friend of Jesus.
You see people lamenting, complaining, whining
and questioning their faith in the presence of others because of their situation
instead of honouring God with their problems before men.
Honouring God.
Thank You, Jesus.
That is a Christian.
But others...
Oh...oh....oh...oh...oh!
OK, you teach me this language.
Instead of honouring God with their situation before men
as Daniel did…
Ask Daniel.
Let me take you to the lion's den and ask Daniel.
Ask Daniel and he would tell you what happened in the lion's den.
Ask Paul and Silas and they would tell you what happened in the prison.
They were singing and their hands and legs were chained.
Thank you.
They were singing, creating a wonderful atmosphere
while their legs and hands were chained
because they knew there was something better beyond their situation.
Even if God allows it as a trial,
that is, if God allows your situation as a trial,
we must not think it strange and doubt our Guide.
Because of your situation,
don't cut off your dependence on God,
your duty to God,
your communion with God.
Yes.
We are here with different situations.
You are saying because of that sickness, you are not a child of God. No!
Because you are poor, you say you are not a child of God; your prayer is not answered. No!
These are the things satan uses
to take you out of your position.
Your enemies think they are hurting you
not knowing that their hatred, evil plans, envy and jealousy
are weapons God uses to preserve you.
South Korea Crusade
There is one person who can get you out of God's will;
that is yourself.
Sickness cannot get you out of God's will.
Your enemy, satan, demon cannot get you out of God's will.
There is one person who can get you out of God's will;
that is yourself.
Let me take you to the book of Luke 22:32.
Here we end our message for today, and we can move around to attend to the sick.
We believe God will give us the grace to continue.
I should not talk as if I knew that we would continue.
Oh yes.
Let's go to the book of Luke 22:32.
"But I have prayed for you, Simon, that your faith may not fail."
What is good for Simon in the Bible is equally good for all.
He says, "I pray you, Simon, that your faith will not fail".
This means there is something that will challenge our faith -
something that will test our faith.
This is what we are going through now.
This is a prophetic word that a time like this – a time for sickness, affliction, poverty to test…
So, why are we lamenting when sickness comes to test?
Why are we murmuring
when hardship comes, as a Christian, to test,
when the Bible says, I pray your faith will not fail?
He never promised to keep us away from trouble.
He never promised to keep us away from tribulation.
What you are going through, He never promised to keep you away from it.
He never promised to keep us away from all these – hardship, trouble
but He promised to see us through, if you are with Him.
South Korea Crusade
I'm hearing the voice of the Holy Spirit.
He says I should go and attend to the sick ones.
Thank you.
South Korea Crusade
I think I need to "chip in" a word before we go for healing.
Healing, deliverance and all of God's blessings
are hindered by the way and manner we go about the issue of money.
South Korea Crusade
I repeat.
Healing, deliverance and all of God's blessings
are hindered today
by the way and manner we go about the issue of money, money, money.
South Korea Crusade
No one can give money from his heart before healing.
Anybody that gives money before healing is giving that money on a condition -
heal me, have money.
Healing and God's blessings should not be exchanged with money.
When we give freely
as we have been given freely,
God will raise His people to bless us abundantly.
Anything that does not come from the heart is a sin.
If someone gives money before healing, he is not giving it from his heart;
he is giving it to receive healing.
South Korea Crusade
Anything that is not from the heart is a sin.
This is why it's so difficult to receive healing and deliverance today.
All this - God's blessings, are hindered by the manner and way we go about money.
Thank you.
RV- Jacqueline Margaret 21/06/18